OVERVIEW

STEPHEN CHARLES

I'm a proficient *pythonista* with a background in mathematics, astrophysics and computer science. Particular expertise in managing machine learning pipelines with large data sets involving time series analysis, computer vision and NLP, in addition to interpersonal skills from a range of hospitality roles. Take a look at my Portfolio and GitHub for examples of recent passion projects!

EMPLOYMENT

Feb 2022 - Now

Innovative Technologies – Manchester - Remote

Position

Machine Learning Engineer

Stack Duties Python, Pytorch, Keras, Tensorflow, Numpy, Pandas, Sklearn, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Git, Bash
• ICU performs accurate age verification to automate associated policy and allow access to age

- restricted purchases and premises, through an ensemble of various ML algorithms.

 Implemented bespoke methods from cutting edge research in SVM's, CNN's, and Bayesian Linear
- Regression which allow for statistically robust age verification.

 Designed a system by which spoof detection was achievable through the use of belief propagation
- and anomaly detection.
- Deployed trained models in resource-constrained environments, optimised through quantization.
- Worked remotely in an agile, communicative, and self-directed manner as part of a collaborative, interdisciplinary, diverse, and geographically-dispersed team.

June - Sept 2020

Facebook (Meta) – London - Remote

Position

Data Scientist, Analytics Intern

Stack Duties Tableau, SQL, Python, Amazon Web Services, Google Cloud Platform
• Performed large-scale data analysis to extract useful business insights.

- Identified the ones which were actionable, suggesting recommendations, and influenced the direction of the business by communicating the results to cross-functional groups.
- Classified leads so that the team could work on the most valuable cases, and suggested improvements in the tools and techniques to help scale the team.
- Created dashboards with Tableau on data obtained via SQL queries.

EDUCATION

Ост 2021 – 2022

Data Science - University of Bath

MSc

Distinction, Master of Computer Science

DISSERTATION

"Decoding EEG Imagination and Perception Signals", Neuroscience

The aim was to explore if decodability of an EEG classification signal depends on an individuals capacity for vivid imagination, presented alongside a comparison of stochastic and deterministic machine learning models.

Modules

Statistics for Data Science - Probability and statistics, with a focus on translating real-world problems into a mathematical framework in data science contexts.

Machine Learning - Covered both supervised and unsupervised machine learning algorithms from Bishop, including how to develop, evaluate and deploy trained models. The second semester involved advanced techniques focused on neural networks with both regression and classification.

Reinforcement Learning - Implemented various agents to solve environments from Sutton & Barto, including Dynamic Programming, Temporal Difference and Deep-Q Learning.

Bayesian Machine Learning - Implemented approaches such as bayesian inference, importance sampling, monte carlo, and confidence interval predictions both from scratch and using bambi.

 $\mathbf{Oct}\ \mathbf{2020} - \mathbf{2021}$

Astronomy and Astrophysics - University of Manchester

MSc

Distinction, Master of Physics

 $\operatorname{Research}$

Published a program to facilitate the data acquisition and analysis pipeline for TESS automatically, dubbed firefly (the best Sci-fi show!), which applies nested sampling (dynesty) to find best fit variables (transitfit) between the host star and exoplanet.

Sept 2016 - 2020

Mathematics with Computer Science – University of Nottingham

 $\mathrm{BSc}/\mathrm{MMath}$

First-Class Honours, Master of Mathematics

Research

Dissertation involved working with python to numerically solve spherical cavitation bubble collapse.

 $S_{EPT} 2014 - 2016$

Space Engineering - Loughborough College

A-Levels

Mathematics A* · Further Mathematics A · Physics A · Engineering A

A specialised course focused on Engineering with guest lectures at the Space Centre in Leicester.

GENERAL TECH STACK

AWARDS AND QUALIFICATIONS

LANGUAGES	Python, C++, SQL, LATEX	2022	DataCamp: Data Science Track
PACKAGES	Numpy, Pandas, SciPy, AstroPy	2022	AWS DeepRacer Student
ML PACKAGES	Sklearn, Tensorflow, PyTorch	2021	Kaggle Competitions
Data Viz	Tableau, Seaborn	2020	Tableau Desktop Specialist
SCIENTIFIC	Matlab, R, Fortran, Mathematica	2016	Full UK Driving Licence
CLOUD	GCP, AWS	2015	Grade 8 Violin

PUBLICATIONS

2020 - Now SPEARNET - University of Manchester

Actively contributing to exoplanet detection in the spearnet collaboration (Spectroscopy and Photometry of Exoplanetary Atmospheres Network). Spearnet is a UK-Thai collaboration which is using a heterogeneous telescope network to select and follow-up exoplanet transiting systems.

Author

Co-Author Hayes, J J

Hayes, J J C, E Kerins, J S Morgan et al. (2021) "TransitFit: an exoplanet transit fitting package for multi-telescope datasets and its application to WASP-127 b, WASP-91 b, and WASP-126 b", 1–14.

Academic Work Experience

Autumn 2018 Scholarship - National University of Singapore

Scholarship Obtained a scholarship to study a crash course in Korean language for 5 weeks and to learn about

the culture and history of the changing landscapes of Singapore. Upon completion, applied to spend

the Autumn semester here successfully.

Sept 2017 - 2019 Physics Outreach - The University of Nottingham

Outreach I began, on a voluntary basis, promoting physics via social media which eventually evolved into a

paid role in which I mediated with events staff in the department to ensure successful participation.

Part of the role was ensuring inclusivity, and how best to target minority groups.

Summer 2018 Magical Maths - St Mary's Catholic Primary School, Nottingham

Outreach Organisation of weekly sessions to promote mathematics to primary school children, in line with

the national curriculum.

Summer 2014 Research Intern - Space Research Centre, The University of Leicester

INTERN During my first college year I gained work experience at the University of Leicester Space Research

Centre, assisting in the development of an astrobiology rock-sampling tool called SPLIT for use on

Mars.

Dr. Eamonn Kerins

INTERESTS

PHOTOGRAPHY Avid adventurer and keen Music Self taught Guitar, Piano, Violin.

astronomer. This hobby pushes the $$A_{\rm RT}$$ Into optical illusions like the works of

boundaries of my interest in both. Escher, Bridget Riley etc.

Exploring the peaks, lakes and Literature Love the classics, Jules Verne, H.P.

Dr. John Holt

anywhere with hills. Love to spend Lovecraft, H.G. Wells etc.

weeks away camping.

General Into Sci fi and anything spacey!

REFERENCES

Name

HIKING

TITLE Senior Lecturer Research Professor Research Engineer

EMAIL eamonn.kerins@manchester.ac.uk chrisharris57@msn.com jmch1@le.ac.uk

University of Manchester University of Southampton University of Leicester Department of Physics Department of Engineering Department of Physics

Prof. CJ Harris

PhD, DSc, FREng, Fellow PhD, FREng

34a Great Whyte Ramsey Cambridgeshire PE26 1HA United Kingdom

Reference: **Data Scientist**Date: Sunday 28th August, 2022

Dear RegGenome,

Before I started academic study I used to run a server for Ultima Online, primarily written in C++. As such, the server was highly customisable, and with the source code from another server I painfully merged two incompatible SVN's together to create one. Just by comparison alone I was able to get used to the logic and constructs that formed the language. Browsing through the many lines of code and merging was a very slow process, but it allowed me understand slightly different methods of doing things. It was almost like learning through reverse engineering. I like to follow the concept of learning by doing. Of note, I took interest in the AI constructs and pathing algorithms adopted, to try and create realistic npcs to fill the world.

My undergraduate studies primarily focused on Mathematics in its purest form, to which I supplemented this by taking extra modules from physics to practice its application. In my final year I took a formal C++ course to take what I had learned from my game server days and apply it to my reading during undergraduate study. Suddenly very nasty equations were efficiently solved! I think data analysis in this aspect fascinates me. My dissertation project involved the inter-facial perturbations of a spherical bubble, to which an approximate formula was derived. As with most fluid dynamics problems, the solution required numerical analysis. I was able to apply my previous knowledge and reverse engineering, adapting to new problems, using the many libraries and pseudo code available in literature.

Astrophysics became my next programming achievement. Extreme care, and background knowledge was required in the handling and use of very large data sets. The precise information needed extracting and filtering, by which a human doing such by hand would be very laborious! Specifically, I worked in exoplanet research, fitting light curves to improve on the planets already proven to exist. The hope is that with a greater sensitivity, more interesting and varied data will provide confirmation of exomoons and through transit timing variations, more planets! In this field I have written a self-contained python EDA pipeline (firefly) for a transit fitting program (TransitFit) to automate the data collection it requires to run. This was written in python, which has quickly become my favourite language. It can currently fit TESS lightcurves with a nested sampling routine, using a Bayesian machine learning approach. In the future I hope to expand the functionality by allowing simultaneous fitting of multiple space based and ground based telescopes.

I'm keen to apply to the position of Data Scientist at RegGenome because I feel that my past experience would be an asset to your team. My technical background paired with your current expertise would be of great benefit to us both, and I feel that at RegGenome I would meet like minded individuals who share the same passions for Data Science.

I am hopeful these considerations will be of benefit in the application process. Should you require more depth than supplied here, please visit my GitHub and Portfolio.

Kind Regards,